# Yogesh Kumar

## Fullstack Developer

#### Contact

yoku2010@gmail.com +91-8130935784

S yogesh\_kumar1988

yogesii\_kainariso

🚨 online resume

**?** yoku2010

🖹 yoku2010

in yoku2010

**(1)** yoku2010

## Total Experience

9 Years and 8 Months

#### Skills

- proficient
  - Python
  - JavaScript
  - Angular
  - o ECMAScript 6
  - TypeScript
  - o Django
  - NodeJS
  - o ExpressJS
  - o ReactIS
  - o Redux
  - Jest
- comfortable
  - jQuery
  - Jasmine
  - Mocha
  - ChaiHTML5
  - o CSS3
  - SASS/SCSS
- Sparkfamiliar
  - Machine Learning
  - MongoDB
  - MySQL
  - o Git
  - o D3
  - Webpack
  - o AWS

## Languages

- native
- Hindi
- intermediate
  - English

## **Objective**

A skilled and reliable software engineer bringing in-depth experience in software development, maintenance, and the ability to work with new and existing codes. Comfortable in leading small teams, coordinating with design and marketing teams, and working with clients.

## **Selected Projects**

PBS KIDS - Progress Tracker | Data analytical and storage system

pbskids.org

- Analytical tool to store, validate game & video events data and generate various reports.
- Research & development and made different POCs using Spark, Kibana, Logstash and Elasticsearch.
- Technical specs are Python, Django, MySQL, Cassandra, RabbitMQ, and jQuery.

PBS KIDS - BOSONJS | Data computation system

pbskids.org

- Realtime calculation (algorithms) on game, video & activities data and provide stats.
- Technical specs are NodeJS, ExpressJS, jQuery, RethinkDB, Redis, and RabbitMQ.

PBS KIDS - FASCIA  $\mid$  System monitoring tool

pbskids.org

- Monitor & administration web applications and their components.
- Technical specs are NodeJS, ExpressJS, ReactJS, Redux, ECMAScript, D3, SASS/SCSS, and MongoDB.

PBS KIDS - GRAVITON | Event data analytics system

pbskids.org

- Data analytics system to store events in the database and compute various aggregate functions to generate stats for a game player.
- Technical specs are AWS Lambda Functions, DynamoDB, NodeJS, and TypeScript.

Shine | Online recruitment portal

shine.com

- Job seeker can register, create their profile and apply for jobs
- Recruiter can register and find best candidates.
- Technical specs are Python, Django, jQuery, MySQL, and MongoDB.

Unified Network Management Platform | Configure, manage and monitor network devices

TININID

- Robust & scalable platform for configuring and monitoring the IP-based devices present in any enterprise or carrier-grade network.
- Search the newly installed network elements, allow to manage, group the network devices/nodes based on their location and type
- $\bullet \;\;$  Integrate any number of devices with UNMP easily and seamlessly.
- An efficient event management system (EMS) for all the SHYAM DATA PRODUCTS.
- Technical specs are Python, Django, jQuery, MySQL, Nagios, RRDTool, SNMP, UPnP, and TCP.

## **Experience**

08/2014 - Cont.

#### Excelsoft Technologies Pvt. Ltd. $\mid$ Lead Engineer

Noida

- Coding, mentoring and helping team members by establishing processes/agendas, planning work, and reviewing tasks.
- Involved in both front-end and back-end developement.
- Involved in technical training programs.
- Client interaction for daily stand-ups, requirement gathering, and following an agile methodology.

11/2013 - 06/2014

eTouch Systems Pvt. Ltd. | Software Engineer

Gurugram

 Developed a Training Project Management System for CISCO using Python, Django AngularJS and MySQL.

11/2012 - 11/2013

HT Media Ltd. | Sr. Software Engineer

Gurugram

• Developed candidate module of shine.com using Python, Django, jQuery and MongoDB.

04/2010 -10/2012 Codescape Consultant Pvt. Ltd. | Team Lead

Jaipur

- Developed web applications and network management system using Python, Django, and
  Nagios
- Roles were training delivery, leading team, Client interaction, back-end, and front-end development.

# **Education**

2009 B.E./B.Tech | Information Technology

University of Rajasthan

- Studied Algorithm, Computer languages, Operating System and Data Structure.
- From Govt. Engineering College, Ajmer with 65.15% marks.

2005 12th | Science & Maths

RBSE

- Studied Physics Chemistry and Mathematics.
- From D.A.V. Senior Secondary School, Ajmer (Rajasthan Board of Secondary Education) with 60.77% marks.